Guide to the Historical Game Collection M2080
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Historical game collection
1982-2009
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
M2080
5 Linear Feet (10 boxes)
Collection of video games, including games made by Sega, Nintendo, Atari, and others.
Content Description
A collection of historical games and software. Includes video games and software for the Sega Genesis 32X, Sega Master System, Nintendo Super Famicom, Sega Saturn (NTSC-J), Nintendo Dsi (NTSC-U/C), Nintendo Family Computer, Atari 5200 Super System, various computer systems, and more. Most of the games and software are accompanied by their packaging and/or user manuals. A few games are preview copies. The collection also includes a few press kits.
The games have been listed as new accessions are added and are not in any particular order. Furthur accruals are expected.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased; 2015-2017. Accessions 2015-080, 2016-002, 2016-003, 2016-014, 2016-097, 2016-121, 2016-122 and 2017-206.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Games are not available for playing, but the media and accompanying materials may be examined for research purposes. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use.
Computer games -- History.
- Doom, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
- Land of Illusion starring Mickey Mouse, 1992 (Box 1)
- F-Zero, 1990 (Box 1)
- Virtual Fighter, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
- System Flaw, 2009 (Box 1)
- ゼルダの伝説 = Zeruda no Densetsu, 1986 (Box 1)
- Timothy Leary's Mind Mirror, 1986 (Box 2)
- Mario Bros. Atari 5200 Super System game, 1983 (Box 2)
- Orbital Mech manual and 3.5 inch floppy disk, 1986 (Box 2)
- Star Wars: The Empire Strikes Back game cartridge by Parker Brothers, 1982 (Box 2)
- The Zork Anthology compact disc for DOS/Macintosh, 1994 (Box 3)
- Baldur's Gate II game for Mac, 2000 (Box 3)
- Pac-Man for the Atari 5200, 1982 (Box 4)
- RealSports Tennis for the Atari 5200, plus manual, 1983 (Box 4)
- Donkey Kong for the Atari 7800, Copyright 1981, 1983, Nintendo; Copyright 1988, Atari Corporation. (Box 4)
- Blue Lightning for the Atari Lynx, Copyright 1989, Epyx, Inc. Lic. to Atari Corporation. (Box 4)
- Dogz: Your Computer Pet, 18 games or software media including: TETRIS; Dogz: Your Computer Pet; Shanghai (no software included); IBM Storyboard Plus; Lemmings; Halo: Combat Evolved; Macintosh System Software 7.0; Sid Meier's Civilization; Full Spectrum Warrior; Afterlife: The Last Word in Sims; 3D Landscape; Monkey Island 2; X-COM UFO Defense; Outside In; Sid Meier's Colonization; Sim City; Amiga Forever Premium Edition 2016; C64 Forever Plus Edition 2016 (Carton 5)
- C64 Forever Plus Edition 2016 (Carton 5)
- Amiga Forever Premium Edition 2016 (Carton 5)
- TETRIS: the Soviet challenge (Carton 5)
- Shanghai (no software included) (Carton 5)
- IBM Storyboard Plus (Carton 5)
- Lemmings (Carton 5)
- Halo: combat evolved (Carton 5)
- Macintosh System Software 7.0 (Carton 5)
- Sid Meier's Civilization (Carton 5)
- Sid Meier's Colonization (Carton 5)
- Full Spectrum Warrior (Carton 5)
- Afterlife: the Last Word in Sims (Carton 5)
- 3D Landscape (Carton 5)
- Monkey Island 2 (Carton 5)
- X-COM UFO Defense (Carton 5)
- Outside In (Carton 5)
- Sim City (Carton 5)
- Myst: the surrealistic adventure that will become your world (Box 6)
- Diablo (Box 6)
- Ultima IV: quest of the Avatar (Box 6)
- America's Army: Rise of a Soldier, 2005 (Box 7)
- America's Army: Special Forces, 2003 (Box 7)
- Assassin's Creed, 2007 (Box 7)
- Atari Anthology, 2004 (Box 7)
- Battlefield 2: Modern Combat, 2005 (Box 7)
- Bioshock, 2007 (Box 7)
- Bully, 2006 (Box 7)
- Chrono Cross, 1999 (Box 7)
- Conan, 2007 (Box 7)
- Command & Conquer 3: Tiberium Wars, 2007 (Box 7)
- Counter-Strike: Condition Zero, 2004 (Box 7)
- The Document of Metal Gear Solid 2, 2002 (Box 7)
- Donkey Kong 64, 1999 (Box 7)
- Doom 3, 2005 (Box 7)
- Frank Herbert's Dune, 2001 (Box 7)
- The Godfather: The Game, 2006 (Box 8)
- Grand Theft Auto III, 2001 (Box 8)
- Grand Theft Auto IV, 2008 (Box 8)
- Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas, 2004 (Box 8)
- Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas, 2005 (Box 8)
- Grand Theft Auto: Vice City, 2002 (Box 8)
- Halo: Combat Evolved, 2001 (Box 8)
- Halo 2: Limited Collector's Edition, 2004 (Box 8)
- Halo 2 Multiplayer Map Pack, 2005 (Box 8)
- Halo 3 Limited Edition, 2007 (Box 8)
- Kingdom Hearts, 2002 (Box 8)
- Kingdom Hearts II, 2005 (Box 8)
- Lara Croft: Tomb Raider Anniversary (Eidos Press Kit), 2007 (Box 8)
- Left Behind: Eternal Forces, 2006 (Box 9)
- The Legend of Zelda: Four Swords Adventures, 2004 (Box 9)
- The Legend of Zelda: Link to the Past (Re-release), 1996 (Box 9)
- The Legend of Zelda: The Wind Waker, 2003 (Box 9)
- Mass Effect (Limited Collector's Edition), 2007 (Box 9)
- Metal Gear Solid 2: Substance, 2003 (Box 9)
- Metroid Prime, 2002 (Box 9)
- Minority Report: Everybody Runs, 2002 (Box 9)
- Paper Mario, 2001 (Box 10)
- Pokemon Stadium, 2000 (Box 10)
- Rez, 2001 (Box 10)
- Spore Creature Creator, 2008 (Box 10)
- Super Mario Sunshine, 2002 (Box 10)
- Tabula Rasa, 2007 (Box 10)
- Tetris 2 (Box Only), 1993 (Box 10)
- Yu-Gi-Oh! World Championship Tournament 2004 (Box 10)
- Army Men Air Attack 2 Press Kit, 2000 (Box 10)
- Halo 2 for Windows Vista Review Build, 2007 (Box 10)
- Unreal Tournament (Beta 15 preview disc), 2000 (Box 10)